

Gysbert Lucas Olivier

Software Craftsman

Last update: Tue May 08 2018 20:46:54 GMT+0200 (South Africa Standard Time)
The online version is available at

http://LucasScript.github.io/my-cv-repo

Profile

I have more than 4 years' employment experience in software development. From June 2017 I entered a roll where I developed mainly in a full stack environment. Prior to this I was in a roll where I developed in a Java environment.

My time working in the financial industry has taught me a lot as I improved legacy and built new features to assist the business to grow in providing better client experience.

I like to see myself not just as a developer but as a software craftsman that code by principles that improve the current and empowers the future.

When I'am not coding I enjoy cycling, photography and gaming.

Employment

Software Developer at Investec

January 2014 - Present

Worked 3+ years on Java/Xml base system. I subsequently moved into a fullstack angular and node is environment.

Intern Developer at FOXit (Pty) Ltd

November 2012 - December 2012

As a holiday job I worked as an unpaid intern and developed a basic Windows 8 application.

Project Assistant at Scadco

July 2011 - July 2011

During holidays I assisted in setting up computers and systems in schools.

Education

Honors Bachelor of Science(BSc) in Computer Science and Information Systems at North-West University

2013

My year project was on Navigation with Augmented and Virtual Reality. I developed an Android Application for a proof of concept.

This degree's subjects were focused on SQL databases, computer security and image processing.

Bachelor of Science(BSc) in Information Technology at North-West University

2010 - 2012

This degree's subjects were focused on JAVA and C# languages, and some business focused subjects.

National senior certificate at High School Ben Vorster

2005 - 2009

Subjects included: Afrikaans, English, Mathematics, Life Orientation, Engineering Graphics and Design, Information Technology and Physical science

References

Available on request

DETAILS
Sandton, 2191, South Africa
+27718951225

lucasoli4@gmail.com

DATE/PLACE OF BIRTH 1991-01-30 / South Africa

NATIONALITY South African

GITHUB LINKEDIN

LANGUAGES English

Afrikaans

SKILLS Team work Communication

TECH Java, XML, SQL

HTML, CSS, SCSS

JavaScript, TypeScript

Node.js, Angular.js

Bootstrap

HOBBIES Cycling Photography Arduino Projects